Guide to the Stanford University, Hopkins Marine Station, Records SC1301
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Hopkins Marine Station, Records
1903-1965
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hopkins Marine Station
Fisher, Walter K. (Walter Kenrick)
Bolin, Rolf L. (Rolf Ling), 1901-1973
SC1301
.75 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
Hopkins Marine Station is the marine laboratory of Stanford University, located in Pacific Grove, California. Founded in 1892, it the oldest marine laboratory on the US Pacific Coast.
Scope and Contents
Collection primarily consists of early Hopkins Marine Station Resident Director Walter Kenrick Fisher’s correspondence; also includes clippings, reprints, photographs, and a partial typescript of “Life Between Tides.”
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Administrative transfer, 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Marine biology -- Research; Hopkins Marine Station; Fisher, Walter K. (Walter Kenrick); Bolin, Rolf L. (Rolf Ling), 1901-1973
- Records, Accession ARCH-2015-095
  - Grant proposal to NSF requesting supplement to NSF G-17465, Research and Training in Biological Oceanography, 1962-10-5 (Box 1)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2017-009
  - W.K. Fisher, U.S. National Museum - correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - W.K. Fisher correspondence, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - W.K. Fisher correspondence, 1935-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - W.K. Fisher, 1903-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - W.K. Fisher correspondence, 1923-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - W.K. Fisher correspondence + tss, 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - John H. Phillips, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Life Between Tides" - Chapter IX (tss + correspondence), 1939-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dredging, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tage Skogsberg - correspondence, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Discovery lists, 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Stanford Illustrated Review" - clipping, 1931 May1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - HMS History, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Space Program for Hopkins Marine Station", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reprints, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Slides, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)